

ROY LEE

PROFESSIONAL WEB ENGINEER
—

ABOUT ME

Senior-level web developer with 7+ years of experience in software engineering and web development.

Experienced with architecting, developing and implementing interactive websites while applying SEO knowledge to engage users and drive organic traffic.

Advanced knowledge of multiple programming languages, frameworks and extensive familiarity with several database structures.

CONTACT

mastercoderoy64@gmail.com 1 Lakeside Dr, Oakland, CA, 94612

PERSONAL

Flexibility
Communication
Collaboration
Creativity
Efficiency
Accountability
Self-Innovation
Self-Starter
Critical-Thinking
Problem-Solving

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sep 2010 – Jul 2014

University of California, Riverside Riverside, CA

WORK EXPERIENCE

FULLSTACK ENGINEER

Nexxo Financial, Chicago, IL / Feb 2019 - Jun 2021

- Worked on the development and implementations of decentralized application with React, Solidity and Truffle.
- Architected, developed and deployed web / mobile application with Express.js, PostgreSQL, React, React Native, Mobx and Typescript.
- Implemented unit testing and e2e testing in React projects with testing-library in React, Enzyme and Cypress.
- Architected and developed microservices using Koa.js,
 MySQL, Prisma, Elastic Search and maintained monolith web application with Django and React.

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER

Loadsys Solutions, Chicago, IL / May 2016 - Feb 2019

- Led development team in delivery of various **Django-React** and **MERN** stack projects requiring close cooperation among members to share information and develop solutions to meet broad array of deliverables.
- Designed, developed and deployed 4+ full-stack web applications according to business objectives and needs of various clients with React, Vue, Django, Express.js.
- Improved the page speed by 15% for the ecommerce site that generates \$25M annually in revenue by implementing Code-Splitting and Optimizing performance with React, GraphQL and Apollo.
- Implemented SEO in React application for e-commerce site with a catalog of 20000+ products leading to an increase in page views per session of 23% with SSR in Next.js.
- Worked on building customer-facing web application with Express.js, Prisma, Vue.js, PostgreSQL and Node.js.
- Built Progressive Web Application (PWA) with React,
 TypeScript and GraphQL (Relay).
- Deployed several web applications using Docker,
 Kubernetes and AWS





ROY LEE

PROFESSIONAL WEB ENGINEER

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

JavaScript / TypeScript

C / C++

Java

PHP

Python3

Ruby

Solidity

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React / React Native / Vue / Angular
Django / Flask / FastAPI
Ruby on Rails / Sinatra
Node.js / Express.js / Koa / Prisma
Laravel / WordPress
Cypress / Selenium / Puppeteer
MySQL / PostgreSQL / Oracle
MongoDB / DynamoDB
Docker / Kubernetes / Elastic Search
AWS / Azure / Clouding
REST / GraphQL (Relay, Apollo)
Blockchain / Ethereum

WORK EXPERIENCE

NODE.JS DEVELOPER

Loadsys Solutions, Chicago, IL / Sep 2015 - May 2016

- Maintained backend code built with Express.js, MySQL and collaborate with product team to implement new features plan for future products.
- Designed, implemented, documented, and successfully deployed real time application with Node.js and, Socket and WebRTC.
- Worked on MERN stack project as a cross developer with MongoDB, Express.js, React and Node.js.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Loadsys Solutions, Chicago, IL / Apr 2015 - Sep 2015

- Worked on the Payments team to save over 50,000 customers time and improve cash flow through the development of modern, responsive customer experiences using **Angular** and **Ant Design Library**.
- Contributed to the in-house UI library to create reusable React components that saved over 200 hours of development time per month.
- Created a web app MVP for a store delivery management platform with 100+ business customers to create, manage, and monitor deliveries using **React** and **Redux**.

REACT DEVELOPER

Liventus, Inc, Chicago, IL / Nov 2014 - Apr 2015

- Delivered responsive, cross-browser compatible and accessibility compliant websites, achieving 19% faster load time than industry average using **React** and **Flux**.
- Collaborated with the UX/UI design teams to improve the website and applications, increasing conversion rates by 25% using SASS/SCSS and Bootstrap.
- Expanded features, refined code, and improved performance with **React**, producing smoother operations and enhancing user engagement.











































